# **Bitna Keum**

+82-10-3446-3606

beausty23.tistory.com

github.com/BitnaKeum



# **INTRODUCTION**

I am about to graduate from Kwangwoon University. I'm passionate about Natural Language Processing. My long-term goal is to make human-like conversational chatbot, which can even replace a real friend and has various persona. I'd like to deepen my understanding of the field of NLP and do in-depth research, so I'm going to graduate school.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Kwangwoon University**

Bachelor of Engineering, Department of Computer & Information Engineering GPA 4.16 / 4.5

Mar. 2017 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)
Seoul, South Korea

Jul. 2021 - Present

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Oct. 2019 - Dec. 2019

# **WORK EXPERIENCES**

•	Internship at TUNiB Inc.
---	--------------------------

- Building datasets for Korean language models Gangnam-gu, Seoul

Participation in NLP task competitions

Servicing chatbots

Internship at GNC Solution Co., Ltd.

Studying Deep Learning and NLP
 Songpa-gu, Seoul

Developing Q&A Program based BERT

Stock Analysis using LSTM and magic formula

• **Development Part-time Job** at Esoftware Co., Ltd.

Developing .NET framework Application Software
 Songpa-gu, Seoul

Software UI/UX Design

Management of Database by SQL Query

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCES**

• Chatbot Service Nov 2021 – Jan 2022

- Implementing service proposals and deploying models
- Servicing on Kakaotalk using kakao i open builder

#### Solving Math Word Problem in Korean

Sep. 2021 - Oct. 2021

- Making math word problem dataset and mapping to python code
- Fine-tuning to GPT-3

• <u>TUNiB-electra</u> *Jul. 2021 – Sep. 2021* 

- Web scraping, data preprocessing, and data management
- Collected 1.2TB Korean text data
- now we are making TUNiB-GPT

## • Web Scraping Project

Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2021

Building Web Scrawler for many different web site

# • Coin Price Prediction Project

May. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- To predict time-series data, tried various models (CNN, LSTM, Prophet, ARIMA, N-Beats)
- Got the best result using N-Beats with the profit of 2.23 times

### Thanks For Today: smart diary analyzing myself

Feb. 2021 - Feb. 2021

- Participated in SW-central-university Joint Hackathon as a school representative
- Analyzing the text data of diary by NLP and showing it to user
- Extracting the key word/sentence and frequent words from diary, and Visualizing with Wordcloud

#### GAN-based Clothing Design Application Program

Jul. 2020 - May. 2021

- Industry-Academic collaboration project with LG
- Applying StarGAN and Mask R-CNN and Providing service as Web application
- Improved the model architecture of StarGAN, resulted in better performance
- Made the model 35% lighter

#### Consumer-Entrepreneur Connection Web Community

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

- Developing Web for communication between consumer and (prospective) entrepreneur
- Back-end development with Javascript using Node.js
- NoSQL Database management
- Won an Excellence Award in Autonomous Semester Design & Development Project

# **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITY**

# NLP Paper Reading Group 'Jibhyeonjeon'

Jun. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- Intermediate class member
- Our team presented on the topic 'Task-Oriented Dialogue System'

#### Dacon Al Bit Trader Contest

May. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Participated in the competition following the term project in Data Mining class
- Ranked 17th using N-Beats model with the profit of 2.23 times

### • Idea Contest for Utilizing AI

Nov. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Won the 1st prize with the idea of 'Clothing pattern synthesis program using GAN'

# Coding School Tutor

Jan. 2019, Jan. 2021, Feb. 2021, Jul. 2021

- Working as a tutor of C and Python Coding School in Kwangwoon University
- Assisted and coached students in programming practice

# **AWARDS AND HONORS**

2021	President's Award, AI Grand Challenge, ITTP
2021	Encouragement Award, SW portfolio contest, Kwangwoon Univ.
2020	President's Award, Idea Contest for Utilizing AI, Kwangwoon Univ.
2020	Excellence Award, Autonomous Semester Design & Development Project, Kwangwoon Univ.
2021, 2020, 2018	Academic Excellence Scholarship, Kwangwoon Univ.

# **SKILLS**

#### Programming Skills

- Python (Skilled), C/C++ (Skilled), Java, JavaScript, SQL, R
- PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras

# Language Skills

Korean (Native), English (TOEIC 855), Chinese (Beginner)